Heat. Heat.
control.
I did not care.
Goodbye.
Heat. Heat.
Hey
dad.
4.
Now we're coming.
If you want to help
Good luck.
Heat. Hey, Heat.
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat. Heat.
Everything.
Turn.
questions.
>> How much sleep did you get last night?
>> Um, that's irrelevant. No, I'm just
kidding. I don't know. Maybe like four
hours, five.
Couldn't tell you.
Welcome to Charlotte. Have you got any
feedback from how you ended your draft
call last night with
>> Yeah, I don't know if you heard it
actually, but I saw in the media that I
did actually end up getting that on the
call. So, that was funny. But he said in
every single draft he's had, no one's
done that. So, guess that's a first,
right?
>> How How was today? Did you feel the love
back when you got here?
>> No, I really did. It was really awesome.
Especially I keep on saying like I'm
home. Like my brothers are telling me
not to say it now because I've been
saying it so much but it's like it
really feels like home. It feels like I
was meant to be here and you know there
was a path and it was a divine
intervention to get here. So
>> uh from a football perspective, you're
known obviously for your athleticism. Do
you have a favorite like pull or like
spring block from your career? Did you
just remember laying in a block in space
that opened up for a big play? really
that uh I had a like a backside combo
against Old Miss my last year. Uh that
was my favorite block I've ever had. I
think at least for a combo block that it
was and it was really awesome. I still
like I love watching the club. I'm like
yeah that was that was it felt so good
in game two. Like especially as an
offensive lineman having your running
back hit it right off of you was great
feeling.
>> Have you heard from any of the players
your new teammates?
>> I have. I got a couple texts from uh
different players. I facetimed Trevor
actually after it was cuz he was at
Georgia with me and also got a text from
Bryce and Derek Brown a couple different
guys and so uh yeah I did Bryce
>> sorry oh
>> he was just like let's go like excited
to work together and I was like yeah
let's get after it like I'm excited I'm
really excited to just play ball now the
process is over
>> you mentioned something last night about
getting your pad level down a little bit
was that something you had to kind of
work on when playing Gunner.
>> Yeah, I think it was just different. I
mean, I guess they're different
quarterbacks obviously. So, I mean,
he'll probably have a lot much better
time than Gunnar uh had, but I know that
uh playing with pad levels is a good
thing kind of in any way. Like I don't
know if you can really play I mean I
guess you can play too low, but it
definitely helps especially because
defenders can't really get under if
you're playing lower. So,
>> Monro Dave says he likes to put all
sides, especially in the preseason. How
many reps Do you have how much
comfortability did you get at right
tackle prior to your your starting line?
>> Yeah, I mean I was a swing tackle pretty
much my first two years and so I was
getting experienced at both and my
sophomore year I was primarily a swing
tackle. Like I was getting in every
third series and just kind of switching
the middle of a series didn't really
matter and so I was getting good
experience. I probably have like 300
snaps or something at right tackle and I
don't know like 1,600 left. So, it's
definitely a big difference, but uh I'm
comfortable wherever.
>> Is there a player in your players that
you watch maybe at the college level or
at the pro level that you see yourself
as or at least try to take parts of
their game?
>> Yeah, I mean, I want to build up my own
bag. I don't really want to identify
identify myself as just a singular
person, but I like watching Andrew
Thomas, you know, Georgia grad. Um he's
really clean sets and really consistent
with everything. And, you know, I want
to be like Penny Sul in the run game.
And I've always say that. I grew up
watching him as an Oregon fan. Uh, and
so kind of seeing him develop and how
dominant he is in the run game, you
know, I want to apply that to my game,
too.
>> Charlotte, you mentioned getting a
chance to connect with Coach Gilbert.
Going back to your pro day, what set off
the interaction with him?
>> I mean, we were just, you know, really
chopping it up. We had a couple Zoom
calls. Uh, and then just seeing him at
pro day, you know, we grabbed me a
little, we talked a little bit and then
he ended up running the drills and, you
know, we just, you know, we got along
really well and I'm really glad that I
ended up actually being here because,
you know, he told me when I walked in
this morning, he was just like, "Yeah,
know I did not think we were going to
get to you and he's super psyched and
I'm super psyched." So, it's awesome.
>> You talked about last night being thrown
into playing offensive line as a as a
young kid. First of all, when did that
start and when did at what point did you
realize, you know, you're pretty good at
this?
>> I mean, for as long as I can remember, I
mean, they have the weight limit. I
think I was just right over it and I was
like, "Oh, what if I should just drop
like five pounds so I can carry the ball
or something?" Never happened. But, uh,
it was definitely like on the offensive
line, it's like you got to grow a love
for it. Like I I really don't think you
can play offensive line if you don't
love it. Cuz at the end of the day, like
you're playing 75 snaps a game and you
know, you're really only getting noticed
when you mess up. So it's like you got
to take the responsibility of the
position and just kind of give it your
all. So
>> never thrown the ball to you anywhere.
>> No, believe it or not, I was a
quarterback when I was playing flag
football in elementary school. Uh so my
brothers aren't going to give me the
credit for it. Uh but I was definitely
dicing it up when I was in elementary.
What do you learn about playing on the
offensive line?
>> Just kind of playing as a unit. You
know, you get to play with five guys.
It's not just one guy. It's like five
guys can make the play. You know, you,
you know, you might not get all the
credit, like I said, but you know, you
can turn to your other four offensive
linemen, look at each other, and be
like, "Yeah, we did that. Like, we made
that play happen. We opened that hole.
We protect the quarterback long enough."
Like all of those things.
>> You also mentioned um growing up with
your brothers and being in a pretty
athletic household. What was it like
growing up just a a Freeland brother and
having to compete?
>> Yeah, you know, my mom's been saying it
all day. It's like a fright house if you
can imagine. Just, you know, chirps all
the time, bullying all the time. And I
say them bullying me is what got me
here. And you know, they're still going
to claim that. It's like, yeah, we did
this. We did this, right? Uh, no, it was
it was an awesome household. Just
competition. I mean, we'll probably go
back whatever I go back home and hop
back on. Maybe PGA or something and
compete on that or golf. You know, I'm
going to catch up. My brother thinks I
have a long time till I get there, but
I'm definitely going to catch up soon.
He has no idea.
>> Got you.
>> There was a moment when you and Dave, he
said, "I'm going to have to teach you
about keep pounding." What happened
there? Did you Did you Did you not know
about the keep pounding mantra or was
there something that we didn't hear in
that moment?
You know, I thought, you know, I thought
he said keep bounding because at proday
I was with uh coach Gilbert and I like
messed up the drill like once or twice
and so I was thinking there I was like
oh dude they're holding they still
remember the drill and I was just like
probably overthinking it in the moment
and I was just like keep bounding. I was
just like is he talking about the drill
like but now like I'm here like oh you
he's just saying keep pounding. Okay I
get it now. So, a little bit of a
confusion at first.
>> You mentioned that at your position,
people want to bring up the negatives.
You had a struggle in the Notre Dame
game. I think you might have been
playing hurt just the only reason I
asked, what did you learn from that
game? And and were you in fact playing
injured that day?
>> You know, I didn't know. You know, I
learned actually after the game that I
was injured, but I didn't really see as
an excuse for my performance. Um, I kind
of just learned, you know, I had a lot
to go. I had a lot to grow. like I have
a lot to to work on. So, you know, kind
of going from that into labor surgery,
just kind of getting more on the mental
side and just realizing that like, you
know, if I really wanted to, you know,
come out this year like I did, I was
going to take a lot more work. And so,
um, now I really put my head down and
just started grinding. And I really like
it was really tough, I'd say, um, being
injured and coming off such a bad
performance in my book. Even if I was
only three plays, you know, those only
three plays that people care about. So,
um, no, it was definitely a little
tough, but I think it it built me
stronger and, uh, my mentality, uh, and
my next play mentality really has grown
a lot. So, carrying that into the
league, I think, is going to be good for
me.
>> Monroe, with the with the way the
offensive line coaches work, Joe Gilbert
works almost exclusively with the
tackles, and he's going to probably be
really hands-on early in your like
tenure. How much can that help in your
experience when you get that individual
attention and and you get to be molded
into that technique?
>> Yeah, I think it's really important to
like especially get that one-on-one
time. Uh because I think that you can
have like individual periods, at least
in Georgia, we have individual periods,
but it's hard to get hands-on work when
you got so many guys. And you know, now
that I can get some hands-on experience
and kind of slow it down, um, I think
it'll allow me to get, you know, a
little more uh, like the inches, you
know, the the margins and the details
and all of that. It will be a lot better
just because it's a little slowed down.
>> How do you approach coming into a
professional setting where there are
established,
>> you know, I'm going to be an apprentice
now? I'm going to go learn from them. I
mean, they've been there. They've done
it. It's like, who am I to come in here
and act like I've done everything? Yeah,
I haven't done anything. So, I'm going
to come in there. I'm going to learn
from them and I'm going to compete. So,
um you know, it's a good experience and
I think that I'm Yeah, I'm going to be
an apprentice. That's all I got to say.
>> You have a lot of energy and joy. When
you're talking about football and your
love for the game, I'm curious when
you're not playing football, what are
some things you like to do? Kind of who
are you away from the field when you
have some time off?
>> Yeah, sometimes I like uh just to donate
golf balls to the water and golf
courses. um other times in the woods,
but uh for the most part I just kind of
like uh you know I like cooking a little
bit. I don't know if you've seen my
Instagram page, but I made like two trap
cooking videos and it was all right. But
uh
>> trap cooking
>> just like they weren't great. Uh but uh
yeah, no, I do a couple different things
away from the field, but really I just
like to, you know, play ball, you know,
cook some food, play some golf, and uh
>> yeah, that's what I got.
>> What is trap cooking?
>> I I was just saying like the videos
weren't the best quality type of thing.
Not like No,
I'm not I'm not going out there. I'm not
like picking up brokill and stuff.
>> What's your favorite food to cook?
>> Really like any meat. I made some Philly
cheese steaks. You can ask my family.
They were they said they're like a nine.
You guys give them a nine or something
like that. 94. Yeah. No, they're really
good. So, um really I want to start
expanding my bag, you know, just like my
football bag, but uh cooking whatever I
can whenever I can. So, um yeah, pretty
much anything.
>> And when you couple more, please.
>> And when did you start playing golf?
>> Like the last what, two years? I think I
got my first set of clubs in May of 24
and then I really couldn't play that
whole spring because I got labor. So,
um, probably played less than 25 rounds
of golf in my life, but I'm going to be
on an upward curve. Don't worry.
>> If you had to describe yourself to
Panthers fans, how would how would you
do? So,
>> now it might seem a little silly up
here, but let me know when I get on that
football field, it's going to be on.
Like, I'm I'm I'm on there. I'm going to
go give it all I got every single time,
and I'm going to bring that fire. You
know, that's that's why I came and I'm
carrying from Georgia. And I think that
that's what you get drafting the dogs
that we have that urge. You've been to
the goolog at practice. I'm going to
bring it every single day.
>> That you're a Carolina Panther. There's
a lot of stuff going on today.
>> I mean, there is a lot of stuff going I
mean, it's it's slowly starting to get
to me, but I feel like once I have some
time to kind of sit down and process it,
it's going to hit me. Who knows, maybe
the tears will start flying then. I
don't know yet.
>> You have a connection through Chad Greer
to Icky. I wondered what uh Chad has
told you about Icky or had you met Iggy
at all prior to today at or at any
court?
>> Yeah, I mean he was I very brief
connection. He was there my freshman
year of high school. Um he kind of got
me on this whole path to even be playing
college football and now professional
football. And I invited him to my draft
party. I was like, man, it'd be crazy if
I ended up there because Will Gear just
signed there. Um, and so, uh, whenever I
got actually drafted there, it was kind
of surreal, but yeah. No, I not a whole
huge connection with them, but I'm
definitely good to have a ally here
already along with all my Panther
Nation. Is that what y'all guys call it?
Is that Is that the name?
>> Rookies are known for having to like go
out and get snacks for the the offensive
line room, whatever. Now that you're
cooking and maybe want to save some
cash, are you going to cook for your
teammates?
>> Sure. I hope they don't hate on me
though. You know, I am going to I saw
the snack room. Apparently, it's empty,
but I'm going to put them on to some new
snacks. I promise you that's an
offensive line and I know the best
snacks. So,
>> I don't know if you've had them. The
Trader Joe's Takis, like their version
of Takis are unbelievable. It's almost
like I relapse when I eat a bag of them.
It's like I got to keep them away from
me or else it's going to be a problem.
Thank you.